Let's take a look at this little fruit stand example.
我们来看看这个水果摊示例
I have a column of apple sales and one of orange sales.
一列是苹果销量 一列是橘子的销量
To find out how many total fruit I've sold in each order,
要了解每单一共卖出去了多少个水果
I'll create a new column called fruits.
我将创建一个新的列 叫做 fruits
I'll make a formula that adds the apples and oranges for the order,
创建一个公式 将订单的苹果和橘子数量相加
then fill down so that each row has a sum in the column.
然后向下填充 使该列的每行都求和
Taking a closer look at the cells,
仔细看看这些单元格
it turns out that filled formulas have different addresses for each row.
发现填充的公式对于每行都有不同的地址
These addresses are relative addresses.
这些地址是相对地址
They are relative because I'm adding together the cell two to the left,
因为我将靠左的第一个单元格
plus the cell one to the left for my answer cell.
与靠左的第二个单元格相加
If I copy it or fill it down,
如果我向下复制或填充
the answer cell will always look at the cell two to
答案单元格将始终查看靠左第一个单元格
the left plus the cell one to the left and add them.
和靠左第二个单元格的值 并相加
What if I copy the fruit sum cell to some random place?
如果我将水果求和单元格复制到随机的位置呢？
The cells referenced are still relative to the answer cell,
引用的单元格依然相对于答案单元格
two to the left and one to the left.
靠左两个单元格和靠左一个单元格
It's important to be aware of this default behavior in
请务必认识到这种电子表格默认行为
spreadsheets because it's not always what we want.
因为我们并非始终希望是这种情况
Let's try a different problem.
我们再看看另一个问题
Suppose I have some prices set up for our apples and oranges,
假设我对苹果和橘子设定了价格
and now I want to know the total income for each order.
现在我想知道每单的总收入
The formula is pretty straightforward.
公式很简单
The number of apples times the price,
苹果的数量乘以价格
plus the number of oranges times the price.
加上橘子的数量乘以价格
There that looks right. Now, just fill it down.
看起来正常 现在向下填充
Well, something went wrong.
出现问题了
If we look at the formula,
点击公式
we can see what it was.
就看出问题了
The relative address was assumed for the price as well as the daily fruit totals.
价格和每日水果总计都是相对地址
So the price reference for the apples is always three cells to the right,
因此苹果的价格引用始终为右侧的三个单元格
and the price reference for the oranges is always one cell down from there,
橘子的价格引用始终为向下的一个单元格
and that is not what we want.
这并不是我们希望的结果
What we want is to always absolutely use
我们想要的是始终使用
the cell H2 for apple prices and H3 for orange prices.
H2 作为苹果价格 使用 H3 作为橘子价格
What we need is an absolute address for the prices.
我们需要价格为绝对地址
An absolute address is fixed and won't change when it's copied or filled.
绝对地址是固定的 在复制或填充时不会改变
And that is accomplished by entering a dollar sign in
通过在列和行地址前面
front of both the column and row in the address.
输入一个 $ 即可变成绝对地址
The dollar sign in front of the letter tells Excel that the column is fixed,
字母前面的 $ 告诉 Excel 该列是固定的
and the dollar sign in front of the number tells Excel that the row is fixed.
数字前面的 $ 告诉 Excel 该行是固定的
For the price references,
对于价格引用
I'll put a dollar sign in front of both the column letter and the row number.
我将在列字母和行数字前面都加个 $
So both the column and row for the price cells are absolute addresses.
因此价格单元格的列和行都是绝对地址
When I fill down,
向下填充时
the price addresses for the formulas won't change.
公式的价格地址不会改变
They'll stay H2 and H3.
一直是 H2 和 H3
Now, looking at the formulas,
现在看看公式
we can see that the cells referenced are the ones we want.
可以看到引用的单元格是我们想要的单元格